[LOI DICH] Video games can be fun to play.
[LOI DICH] They also can teach people how to settle conflicts peacefully.
[LOI DICH] This is a video game called Food Force.
[LOI DICH] It can be downloaded from the website of the World Food Program.
[LOI DICH] The group's Jennifer Parmaly says the game shows children the difficulty of getting food
[LOI DICH] to areas of conflict.
[LOI DICH] It helps them feel like they could be part of a solution that something was empowering
[LOI DICH] and fun for them.
[LOI DICH] Another video game is called A Force More Powerful.
[LOI DICH] It takes place in a city similar to Belgrade in the former Yugoslavia.
[LOI DICH] Even Marovic designed the game ten years ago.
[LOI DICH] He organized protests against Yugoslav President Slobodan Milosevic.
[LOI DICH] The president resigned after disputed election results in 2000.
[LOI DICH] He was arrested on war crimes charges, but died before his trial was completed.
[LOI DICH] Marovic says his game shows non-violent ways to help remove oppressive governments.
[LOI DICH] Like strikes, boycotts, civil disobedience, street protests.
[LOI DICH] In order to force the regime to either concede or to step down.
[LOI DICH] Marovic says another goal is to win public support.
[LOI DICH] He says the goal is to win the loyalty of people who support the government.
[LOI DICH] Another goal is to keep up the interest of your current supporters.
[LOI DICH] This game deals with the situation in Darfur, Sudan.
[LOI DICH] The conflict in Darfur has displaced three million people.
[LOI DICH] A website called Second Life was used to create the Darfur video game.
[LOI DICH] Players can build their own make-believe world and contact others through voice and text messages.
[LOI DICH] Scott Sexer works for Lyndon Labs, which created Second Life.
[LOI DICH] He says the game lets players come in and see what is taking place in Darfur.
[LOI DICH] Listen to a family which left Darfur and is now in a refugee camp.
[LOI DICH] The Second Life website is able to change text messages in English to other languages.
[LOI DICH] Sexer says he has communicated with people from around the world.
[LOI DICH] Other parts of Second Life help to support democracy and conflict resolution.
[LOI DICH] They include a courtroom where people can learn about legal systems in a democracy.
[LOI DICH] I'm Bob Dodie.